CURRICULUM VITAE

HELLO MY NAME IS VERENA ORTLIEB

I am an UI/UX Designer, currently based in Stuttgart, Germany. I graduated with a Bachelor of Arts in Business Psychology and a Master of Arts in Architecture. Architecture gave me a great design education. But I wanted more; I wanted to understand why people behave like they do and how products could be improved to match their users needs. I decided to study Business Psychology with a main focus on marketing and advertising psychology.

While studying I worked most of the time for different companies. My work helped me to improve not only the theoretical skills of my study but my personal skills like patience and stress resistance as well.

Psychology and design in combination with a never ending will to improve myself have made me a competent and passionate working bee. You can find out more about me and see some things I have done on: www.verenaortlieb.com

SKILLS

I am familiar with various programs and learn new ones quickly and gladly.

SKETCH - advanced ADOBE PHOTOSHOP - advanced **ADOBE INDESIGN - advanced ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR - intermediate MICROSOFT OFFICE - advanced SPSS - intermediate** InVision - intermediate HTML/CSS - beginner

FORMAL EDUCATION

2012 - 2015 - University of Applied Management **Erding Bachelor of Arts Business Psychology (1,8)** Major field of study: marketing & advertising psychology Bachelor Thesis: Digital Neuro Design

2010 - 2012 - University of Applied Sciences Stuttgart **Master of Arts Architecture (1,5)**

2007 - 2010 - University of Applied Sciences Stuttgart **Bachelor of Arts Architecture (1,9)** Best of Bachelor

2005 - Hellenstein Gymnasium Heidenheim Abitur

EXPERIENCE

Since 2015 - UX Designer Freelancer UX research & design, UI design, troubleshooting, idea creation, prototyping, wireframing, testing, iteration, coordination with developers & clients.

2014 - 2015 - Fraunhofer Institute for Industrial Engineering IAO Stuttgart, Germany Research Assistant Creating and analysing online surveys, creating and performing qualitative interviews, literature review, creating presentations, writing scientific papers.

2013 - 2014 - Beaufort 8 GmbH Advertising agency Stuttgart, Germany Intern Applicant management, office management, internet research, creating presentations, organising assessment centres, event management.

2012 - 2013 - Dr.-Ing. Preißing AG Management Consulting Leonberg, Germany Full-time Employee Creating marketing tools, managing internet platforms, assisting the project manager, customer acquisition and care, creating and implementing a survey on the subject "competencies", analysing and optimising internal processes.

2009 - Lederer+Ragnarsdottir+Oei Architectural office Stuttgart, Germany Intern & Working Student Assisting the project team, coordinating with planners, making models, working on architectural competitions.

2007 - 2008 - Rudolph Zauritz & Partner Event Management Stuttgart, Germany Freelancer Event management, internet and location research, accounting, office management.